Max Starikov

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

@ maxim.starikov@gmail.com

S maxim_starikov

github.com/maxistar

♠ https://maxistar.ru

in linkedin.com/in/maxistar/



♥ Berlin, DE

Work experience

Senior Fullstack Engineer

ITEMIS AG

🗖 August 2022 - current time

♥ Berlin, DE

- Backend Web Development; TypeScript, Golang, MongoDB, Azure, AWS, Kubernetes
- Frontend Web Development; VueJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Docker, Jest
- Debugging, Technical Support and Consulting; OpenAPI, Jira, CI/CD

Senior Fullstack Engineer

PlusDental*

SUNSHINESMILE GMBH

- ♥ Berlin, DE
- Frontend Development; PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, ReactJS
- Backend Development; PHP, Symfony, MySQL
- Mobile Development; Android, iOS, ReactNative

Software Engineer

WAYFAIR GMBH

- **☐** September 2018 May 2020
- ♥ Berlin, DE
- Creating of decoupled back end services; PHP, NodelS, .Net
- Creating parcel tracking pipelines; NodeJS, .Net
- Client Portal Development; PHP, Zend Framework, React/S

Senior Frontend Developer

Claver INVESTOR

CLEVER INVESTOR, LLC

☐ August 2017 - September 2018

- ♥ California, USA (Remote)
- Creating of websites and funnel pages for real estate investing educational products; PHP, JavaScript
- Creating number of automated pipelines to automate deployment process; Jenkins, Gitlab
- Setting up various tools to maintain the business infrastructure; Git, AWS, RackSpace

About

I am a passionate Full Stack Software Engineer with 25+ years of experience in Web, Mobile, and Desktop Software Development. I have a strong engineering background in software development. Eager to learn and improve my current tech stack.

Backend developer: I have experience in creating dataintensive Back End services using PHP, JavaScript, and other technologies.

Frontend Experience: I have experience in Front End Development using modern UI frameworks such as VueJS, React, and Angular.

Mobile Development Experience: I have experience in creating Hybrid and native Mobile Applications for Android and iOS.

Skills

■ PHP	>20 Years
JavaScript	>20 Years
SQL	>20 Years
Java/Android	>5 Years
NodeJS	>5 Years
■ C/C++	>3 Years
TypeScript	>2 Year

Languages

■ English	C1
Russian	Native
Deutsch	B2

First page Max Starikov

Frontend Developer

UPWORK GLOBAL INC

- California, USA (Remote)
- Migrating from monorepo legacy code to microservice architecture; PHP, Perl, Java
- Creating number of A/B Tests, optimized server side speed and load time; JavaScript
- Creating New Platform Services; AngilarJS, NodeJS, **CoffeeScript**

Lead of Development Team, CoFounder

IT ACCENT LTD

☐ September 2003 - September 2018 Saratov, RU

- Managing number of projects from start to the end; PHP, JavaScript, Java
- Developing number of web solutions, mobile and desktop apps; PHP, JavaScript, Java
- Developing custom CMS; PHP, JavaScript

Software Engineer

RILA PUBLICATIONS LTD

☐ September 2002 - August 2003 ♥ London, UK

- Web sites development; HTML, PHP, JavaScript, CSS
- Software development; Java, Borland Delphi
- Database administration; *MySQL, MSSQL, MS Access*

Software Engineer

ECONOMBANK JSC

☐ September 2000 - August 2002 Saratov, RU

- Corporate web site development; HTML, PHP, JavaScript,
- Business Software development; Java, Borland Delphi

Education

1995 - 2000

Saratov, RU

Saratov State Technical University; Automatic Control and Informatics in Technical Systems, Diploma of Engineer

2000 - 2003 Saratov, RU

Saratov State Technical University; Postgraduate Education on Chair of Technical Cybernetics and Informatics

C Other Skills

Uρ

MySQL MSSQL PostgreSQL Informix DB C C++ C# Python Bootstrap NPM Composer | HTML5 | CSS | SCSS SASS JavaScript React ReactNative Angular AngularJS Vue Webpack Java Android iOS CleanCode DesignPatterns SQL MySQL MSSQL PostgreSQL MongoDB CI/CD Gitlab Github Linux Azure Kubernetes Docker

♡ Interests

- Cryptocurrencies
- Internet of things
- Embedded systems
- 3D Printing
- Al

Rila

- Natural Languages Processing
- VoIP

∠ Hobby

I devote my free time to my family and my friends.

I build pet various projects: DIY, home automation, mobile and web applications, electronic devices.

I am a big fan of active sports: mountain ski, traveling, hiking, river rafting. I have 1st dan in Aikido, I adore Sci-Fi and nonfiction, play guitar.



